好滴，我们开始了，我们先
Alright, so to get started, we're going to do
把项目建起来，然后我们some basic Project setup, and then we're going to
立即讲一些如何处理
talk immediately about our approach
天气API
working with the Weather API.
好，让我们继续，开始创建
So let's go ahead and get started by just
一个新的项目，不让这影响
creating a new Project and getting that part
我们下面的课程
of it out of the way.
找到正确的
We'll find our correct
空白的应用模板
Blank App template here.
我把它命名为UWPWeather
I'm going to call this UWPWeather.
首先，我们要做的是
Okay, and first thing I'm going to do here
去掉这个帧计数器
is get rid of the frame counter,
像往常一样，打开MainPage.xaml
like always, and I'll open up the MainPage.xaml
MainPage.xaml
我所预想的是一个
So what I have envisioned here is a
相当简单的应用
pretty simple application.
它仅仅是根据你位置
It's just going to have the current weather
获取一下天气状况而已
for the current location you're at.
你可以扩展它，我会演示给你看
You can extend this, and I'll show you how
无论你想让它有多复杂，有多少功能
you can make this as complicated
都能做到
and as feature-rich as you want.
这些内容是很相似的
It's just pretty much more of the same
都是我在这节课，这系列课程中
of what I'm going to show you here
反复讲诉的内容
in this lesson, in these lessons.
我们现在准备就绪
Now that we have that in place,
让我们前进，先最小化项目窗口
I'm going to go ahead and minimize this.
我们将要从一个网站上拉取数据
We're going to pull our data from
这个网站叫 openweathermap.org
a website called openweathermap.org.
顺便一提，如果你要使用它
By all rights, if you're going to use this
在一个商业产品中，你需要登录
in a commercial product, you need to sign up
来获取接口,，如果你每月的请求
for an API, and then if your requests
超出一定数量
are in excess of a certain number per month,
你需要获取一个付费后的
you'll need to get a      ---------------NOT SURE
许可证
paid license.
比如，像我标记的这个，180刀一月
For example, for $180 a month, as I record this,
你可以每分钟调用API 30,000次
you can have 30,000 API calls per minute.
我们只是为了学习
Now, for just our own purposes
和开发的目的，我们不会
in learning and development, we're not
去调用它超过每分钟1200次
going to get any more than 1,200 APIs per minute,
(口误） 但是但是..
API calls per minute, but here again,
你可能需要咨询一下这个网站
you probably need to consult their website.
我不是一个律师，并不清楚所有
I'm not lawyer, I don't understand all
使用它的后果
of the ramifications of this.
这只是单纯学习一下如何
This is purely for us learning how to make
去调用一下Web服务
a call to a web service.
我先不管这可能存在于
So I'm going to leave that part of it
你以及网站之间的问题了
between you and OpenWeatherMap,
先来看一下API
but I'm going to look at the API.
这有可供我们使用There's several different weather APIs
多种不同的天气接口
that we can call.
这里API接口
API will be
基本指的是Web调用的API接口
basically a web-callable API.
意思是我们通过访问URL来完成一次调用
That means we use a URL to make a call,
它会返回给我们或者是JSON格式
and it will deliver back to us either JSON
或者是XML或者其他格式化类型的数据
or XML or some file format that then
然后通过解析它们
we can parse through and use as data
作为应用中的数据使用
for our application.
这有一个当前天气数据
There's current weather data, which is
这是我们要用的
the one we're going to use.
这还有5天每3小时更新的天气预告
There's also 5 day/3 hour forecasts,
16天每天更新的天气预告
16 day/daily forecast,
一大堆API接口
a bunch of other APIs.
先把注意力集中到第一个上
We're going to focus on this first one,
当前天气数据
the current weather data.
你看它的路径是openweathermap.org/current
You can see in the openweathermap.org/current
有很多方法来调用
that there are different ways to make calls
这个API
into this weather API.
比如，当我们只知道
For example, if all we have is the
城市的名字的时候，我们就可以给它
city name, then we can give it
一个像这样的东西
something like that,
在这我们替换掉花括号中
where we replace this curly brace
城市的名字，比如，达拉斯
city name with, for example, Dallas
或者 达拉斯，美国
or Dallas, USA.
我们就会获得天气数据，这个位置的
We would get back the weather, the current weather
当前天气
for that location.
这有一大堆
So there's a number of different ways
我们可以请求的方式
that we can acquire this.
可以使用城市ID
We can use a city ID.
这有一个可供下载和使用的
There's a list of IDs that we can download
ID列表
and utilize.
还可以通过地理坐标来获取天气
We can get to the weather by geographic coordinates.
这就是我们要用的方式
This is the one that we're going to use
因为我们要利用我们设备中
because we're going to use our
内置的GPS功能 或者
device's built-in GPS functionality
定位服务来为我们获取
or location functionality to bring us back
经度和维度
the latitude/longitude for
根据于我们设备的所处位置
the current position of our device,
之后就用这些作为经纬度
and then we'll deliver that as latitude
传递至目标API中
and longitude to this API call,
然后我们就获得了当前的天气情况了
and retrieve back the current weather conditions for it.
我们还可以使用邮政编码
We could also use ZIP code.
这里还有很多高级的情景
There's some advanced scenarios, as well,
然而和我们并没有什么关系
that we're not going to really worry about all that much.
如果你想的话，你可以向下滑
But if you like, you could scroll down,
你可以了解到更多
you could learn a lot about
当你调用其中的接口后
what's delivered back to you
它会返回给你什么样的数据
when you make one of these calls into this API.
时不待我
So let's do this.
我们开始吧，首先
What we'll do, first of all, I'm going to start
输入达拉斯
by saying Dallas
经度，维度
latitude longitude
它会返回给我们坐标
This will give me back the coordinates.
32.77 North.
我想
I think this is a,
这一个是负的西经 96.79
it might be negative 96.79 West,
西经应当是个负数
so West would be a negative.
无论如何，让我先复制一下坐标
But any rate, let me copy those coordinates
放进一个记事本文件中
and put them just in a little notepad file
我把它放镜头外面了
that I have here offscreen so that
这样我可以记住他们
I can remember those.
然后我们回到刚刚的页面
Then what we'll do is we'll come back over here,
找到使用经纬度的API
and I'm going to find this.
实际上我直接点击它开始吧
In fact, let me just go ahead and click on it to start off with.
这里改变一下纬度和经度
Then I'm going to change the latitude and longitude here to 32.77.
经度设置为负的96.79
Then I'll change the latitude to a negative 96.79.
看一下我们得到了什么
I'm going to see what we get back.
你看到我们获得的数据
You can see what we get back
是JSON串
is a series of JSON,
JSON，javascript对象表示法
JSON, JavaScript Object Notation, a very
是网络上一种非常轻量级的数据载体
lightweight way of exposing data
也是最常见的方式之一
over the Internet, very common way of exposing data.
尽管看起来挺复杂的
While this might look a little convoluted,
实际上它遵守一种非常简单的模式
it actually follows a very simple pattern.
让我们这样做吧
But let's do this, I'm going to actually
我要用我的鼠标选择整个
use my mouse to select that entire
json串，包括跑到
JSON string that even runs off to the
窗口右边的一那部分
right-hand side of the screen.
使用Ctrl+C将他们复制
I'm going to hit Control+C to copy this to my clipboard.
然后去另外一个网站
Then I'm going to go to another website
叫json2csharp.com
called json2csharp.
在这里我们能做的事是
What this is going to allow me to do
把JSON粘贴进来，像这样
is to paste in the JSON, right like this,
然后点击Generate，见证奇迹的时候来了
and now when I hit Generate, what'll happen
它创造了一系列的类
is it'll create a series of classes
他们表示了这个JSON串
that represent that JSON.
现在我有了C#的类
So now I have C# classes that I
我就可以反序列化这个JSON串
can then deserialize the JSON
转化成C#中强类型的类
into these strongly typed classes in C#.
而这里你所见是最高层的类
So you can see at the very highest level here,
是一个根类RootObject
I'll have a RootObject.
这个类包含了天气字段的列表
This RootObject will have a List of Weather items.
里面包含了我们创建了其他类
Then there's just a series of
像有一个main类
other classes that were created, a main class,
一个Wind类，一个Rain类，一个Clouds类
a wind class, a rain class, a clouds class
以及一些其他信息
and other information as well.
比如，这个Sys类会给我们提供
For example, this Sys class will give us
县，消息，日出日落时间等等
the county, a message, the sunrise, sunset times.
有成吨的信息量
Just a ton of information.
在main类中，有气压，适度等
In the main class, there's pressure, humidity.
在Weather中，我们可以获得一个图标
In the weather class, we can get an icon
和一个描述根据当前的天气
and a description for the current weather.
我现在要做的就是把这个复制到粘贴板中
What we're going to do is actually I'm going to copy all of this to my clipboard.
我要创建一个东西叫...
I'm going to create something called,
在VS中
here in Visual Studio.
到这来右击一下
I'm going to go over here and right-click.
好吧，换种方式，选择项目，添加类
Actually, let me go ahead and select Project, Add Class.
我要把它命名为 OpenWeatherMapProxy
I'm going to call this OpenWeatherMapProxy.
所谓代理就是中间媒介
A proxy is a go-between.
这可能不是最好的名字
That might not be the best name for this,
但却是第一个跳到我脑子里面的
but it's what came off the top of my head.
在这里，我要粘贴
Inside of this, I'm actually going to paste
刚刚复制的所有类
all these other classes as well.
这里我有个想法，就是
So my thought process here is that I'm going to
这里要有一个静态方法 OpenWeatherMapProxy.
have a static method on this OpenWeatherMapProxy.
它要做的是，当你提供
What it will do is it will, when you give it
经纬度时，它将数据添加到
the latitude and longitude, it's going to feed it
这里我们看到的web服务
to this web service URL
的URL链接中，用我们即将从设备的GPS
that we have here, replacing the latitude
中获得的经度和纬度替换掉里面的数据
and the longitude that we're going to get from our device's GPS,
它就会将传回的JSON格式的数据转换成
and it will convert the data that comes back
一系列的类
in JSON format into a series of classes
之后就可以遍历这些数据
that we can then navigate through, pull out
取出我们需要的, 在屏幕上展示给我们的用户
the bits we want to display to the user on the screen.
希望这些你都听懂了
Hopefully that all made sense.
随着讲解，马上你就会知道该怎么做了
You'll see it as we move forward here.
要实现这个想法
So what I want to do, just as we start
我要做的是
playing with this idea, is,
眼下，我要先把这些东西删除
actually, let me go ahead and get rid of that.
起始布局选用StackPanel
I'm going to start just with a StackPanel.
开始部分我就不想弄得太花哨了
I'm not going to get too fancy with this just to begin with.
把背景色设为HotPink（桃红）
But I'm going to set the Background="HotPink"
因为我看到那个酷酷的演示程序
because I saw a cool demo with
使用的就是hotpink，看起来相当不错
a hot pink background and it looked pretty cool,
然后你马上就能看到这的确
and it's very different from anything else that you'll see
使它与众不同
out there right now.
我要添加一个按钮组件
I am going to add a Button with
内容是“Get Weather"
Content="Get Weather".
还要设置一个点击事件
I'll say set a Click Event.
这一部分我们稍后再做
I think that's all I'll need to do there.
还要添加一个TextBlock
Then I'm going to add a TextBlock.
我们要调用它，命名为
We're going to call this, name this
"ResultTextBlock"
我想你要注意，这并不是
I want you to know that this is not, ultimately,
我想要设计的最终布局
what I'm going to have for my layout.
这些仅仅能够让我去测试
This is just for me to be able to test
发送和截取数据的过程
the process of going out and grabbing
然后还要能展示给用户
the data, and then displaying something to the user.
一旦我能解决最难的部分 .. 我的想法是这样的
Once I can get that hardest, here's my thought process.
无论何时，当我坐下来开始码代码
Whenever I go sit down to build an application,
我总喜欢去攻克这个应用中
I always like to tackle the most difficult aspects
最难的部分, 因为
of the application first because
这样我就能有把握知道
then I get some degree of confidence
它会做什么
that I know what it will do.
开始部分我不做任何假设
I don't make any assumptions beforehand
要去实现什么功能，怎么去实现它
what it's going to do, how it's going to operate.
他们随时可能改变我已经做好的部分
That might adjust the way that I lay things out,
也影响到剩余部分的完成形式
the way that I approach the rest of the application.
所以我总是首先搞定这个应用中
So I always attack the most difficult part
最难的部分
of the application first.
一般说来，最难的往往是
Typically, that's going to be any of the internals
应用中内在的事物
of the application.
它可能是商业逻辑
It's going to be business logic,
它可能是去接入一些数据
it's going to be any data access, it's going to be making
也可能是我们现在要做的，调用Web API
calls out to web APIs like we're doing here.
一旦我将我脑海里面的这些问题
Once I can get those question marks
解决，之后剩下的都是
in my mind resolved, then it makes
水到渠成了
building the rest of the application fairly easy.
现在我要做的是
That's what I'm doing here.
我要创建一些初始化的代码
I'm just going to create some initial code
最终我可能会把这些都丢掉
that I'm ultimately going to probably throw all this stuff away.
无论如何，单击F12跳转过去
So at any rate, let's go ahead and hit F12 there.
这我们有一个按钮点击的事件
So now we have a Button_Click Event,
我们要去调用一下这个
and we're going to make a call into this
OpenWeatherMapProxy 类
OpenWeatherMapProxy class.
这我要创建一个
What I want to do is create a
public static RootObject GetWeather
最终我要传进经度和纬度
Eventually, I'll pass in the latitude and longitude.
现在就做吗？
Should I do that now?
当然，为什么不
Yeah, sure, why not?
我总是忽略这个问题
I can always ignore it.
Whoops, double latitude,
double longitude.
哦，好了
Alright, great.
我要做的事调用一下
So what I need to do is make a call
外部的Web服务
out to this web service.
实现它的方法是通过一个类
The way that I'll do that is through a class
叫做HttpClient
called the HttpClient.
要添加这个，事实上要进去
To add this, I'm actually going to go
一个叫NuGet Package Manager.的工具里面
to Tools, NuGet Package Manager.
去管理一下这个项目中NuGet的包
I'm going to Manage NuGet Packages for the Solution.
搜索一下包名 HttpClient
I'm going to search for the HttpClient.
然后安装它
I'm going to install this.
它问我 是否安装以下全部
It asked me, "Do you want to add all these?"
当然，选是
Yes, yes,
然后接受
and I accept.
好滴
Alright, very good.
现在我要做的事
So now what I want to do is
到这里
go here.
应该能找到了
Should be able to find it.
我要添加一下using声明
I'm going to add that using statement.
然后定义var http = new HttpClient()
We'll go var http = new HttpClient()
像这样\like so.
现在我要做的是
Now what I want to do is
获得一个响应对象
get a response object.
这是HTTP响应消息的类型
This a type HTTP response message.
通过调用GetAsync方法来获取它
I'm going to get to it by calling the GetAsync method.
现在要做的就是给它一个URI
So what we'll do is give it a URI,
字符串类型的URI用来请求
a string URI that we're going to request.
任何时候，只要看到async
Any time we see the word async,
我们应该怎么做？
what do we need to do?
记住公式
Remember the formula.
我们要说，‘我会一直等待结果到来’
We need to say, "I will wait for the results,"
而这意味着告诉我的方法
and that means I need to tell my method
这是一个异步方法,对吧？
that this is an async method, right?
然后我需要给它URL
Then I need to give it the URL.
如果你回想我们这里做的
If you recall what we did here,
我只是为了测试目的
I should be able to just copy this in
复制这个链接的，接下来
for testing purposes, and just go ahead
像这样粘贴到里面
and pop that in there like so.
我们应当就能获取
We should be able to get back
从这个链接里出来的任意数据了
whatever data comes from that,
从这个方法返回的
comes back from that method.
下一步，我需要抓取一个结果
Next up, I need to grab a result,
这个结果将会
and the result will be
从这里面返回出来
what comes back in the
response.Content.ReadAsStringAsync()
response.Content.ReadAsStringAsync().
再一次，看见关键字async
Again, we see the async keyword.
这意味着这句也需要等待
That means we need to await that as well.
现在我把数据变成string格式了
Now I have this in a string format.
现在我需要做的是去序列化
Now what I need to do is I need to serialize.
我需要把所有的字符串
I need to take all that string
这里看到的这些
that we see when we looked here,
把他们转换成一个对象图
and we need to convert that into an Object Graph.
它会引用所有这些类，这个RootObject
All of these, the RootObject and all of the
以及所有其他的对象
objects that it has references to.
要做到这些，需要做的工作是
To do that, what I need to do is
使用一个对象叫做DataContractJsonSerializer.
use an object called the DataContractJsonSerializer.
我需要创建一个叫serializer的对象
I'm going to create something called a serializer.
这个对象用来序列化和反序列化
It's an object that knows how to serialize
JSON格式的数据
and deserialize from JSON.
输入DataContractJsonSerializer
We'll go DataContractJsonSerializer
DataContractJsonSerializer.
你可以看到，这还没有包含在
As you can see, it's not really part of my
这个项目中
Project just yet.
但是，只要我们按Ctrl+"."
However, I can just hit Control+".".
我可以添加这个System.Runtime.Serialization.Json
and I can add that System.Runtime.Serialization.Json
这个命名空间，这样就应该行得通了
namespace, and we should be good to go there.
我需要给它一个
I need to give it the typeof
我想要解析的类的类型
class that I want to work with.
这里，我们就使用RootOject
In this case, we'll start with the RootObject,
它就会引用它需要引用的所有类型
and it'll have references to everything else that it needs.
噢，我需要创建一个新的实例
Oh, we need to create a new instance of that.
现在好了
There we go.
为了实现这个功能，我们还需要做些其他的
Now, in order for this to work, we have to do something,
我们要去修饰这些类
we have to adorn each of these classes
以及他们的属性
and their properties
这里使用一种特别的属性
with special attributes.
要让解析能正常工作，每个类都要
To get this to work right, every class is going to
使用一个叫做DataContract的东西
have to be adorned with something called
来修饰一下
a DataContract.
这个属性在另一个命名空间中
This attribute is in a namespace that we
我们添加一个System.Runtime.Serialization
need to add, System.Runtime.Serialization
它就会告诉serializer对象
This will just tell the serializer that,
嗨，把这个看作类，把这个看作属性
"Hey,treat this like a class, and treat this like a property."
每个属性前添加DataMember
We'll go DataMember for each property.
现在我们需要遍历全部内容
Now we have to go through
在每个类的头顶上，已经每个属性前
and add that attribute on top of every class
都添加上修饰词
and every member of the class.
我要开始做这些工作
I'm just going to go ahead and do this.
这可能要花我1，2分钟的时间
It's going to take me a minute or two
来复制、粘贴到位
of just copying and pasting a lot.
这是一个很常见的事
This is a common thing that you'll do whenever
每当你要去调用一些
you're calling out
Web APIs，你都要这样做
to web APIs.
我不认为你在不懂这些技术的情况下
I don't think that you could be a professional developer
可以去成为一个专业的开发者
nowadays without knowing these techniques,
这些技术像是 序列化和反序列化XML、JSON
being able to serialize and deserialize from XML
或者任意其他惯用的数据类型
and JSON format, and maybe other custom formats,
像是一些二进制的格式
too, like some binary format.
这都是应该藏到你腰包里面的重要技能
It's a pretty crucial skill to have in your toolbelt.
这只是一种
This is just one
能够解决问题的方法
possible way to go about this.
不久之前，我见过一个
I see something that caught my eye
引人注目的东西
just a moment ago.
它激起了宝宝伤心的过往(づ￣ 3￣)づ
It spurred a memory of frustrations past.
稍后我们再回到这个话题上来
Let me get back to it here in a just a second.
这有些东西我要去改一下他们
There'll be some things that I want to change
的名字，我不知道我们使用的
the names of that I don't like how they're
那个工具是如何去
automatically named by that
自动生成名称的
tool that we used,
就是那个免费的网站that free website that converts
可以把JSON转换成POCO（简单初始C#对象）类的那个
your JSON into C# POCO classes.
比如这里这个元素
Yeah, for example, this item here
有一个非法的命名
has an invalid name.
事实上，我要做到就是
In fact, what I'm going to do is just
把它完整的注释掉
comment this out completely.
我不总会这样做的
I'm not going to even use this at all.
Hopefully, the deserializer,
the DataContractJsonSerializer
will just say, "Oh, okay, they don't have a class for that.
"We'll just ignore that," as it tries to pair up
all of the data
that it has with all the class
and property names.
So that's the only thing that I think
I was concerned about.
Let's go ahead and continue on here.
Now what we're going to need to do is get
a MemoryStream.
New MemoryStream.
Let me go ahead and hit Control+"."
on my keyboard
and add the System.IO namespace.
I want to tell it that we're working
with a certain type of Encoding,
specifically, the UTF-8 Encoding.
We're going to call GetBytes.
The reason why we're doing this
is kind of a long story.
I don't really want to talk about it
at the moment.
Most of the time, whenever you're grabbing JSON
and you're working with it, you're going to need
to work with the,
the way that the text is encoded is just UTF-8,
so you'll often use this similar line of code to this.
Just keep that in mind.
Finally, now that we're ready to accept
a MemoryStream, and a Stream
is just a
straw.
It allows us to just have data come in and go out.
Whenever you have things that are happening
at two different speeds, you have something
sending data at a different rate of speed
than something accepting data, you use a Stream.
Here we're going to use a MemoryStream.
We're just going to keep everything in memory
until it all gets sorted out.
Data will go in one end, and then it'll be taken out
as it's needed on the other end.
Finally, we're going to go ahead and do,
get the actual data out of the serializer.
ReadObject
and
let's also then cast that
to a RootObject.
Then we're going to return the data.
So I realize this is pretty meaty stuff here.
It looks like there's one last thing that I need to do.
If I hover my mouse cursor over this,
we've created an async method,
but we've not adorned
the return object as a Task.
So we need to say, actually, what we're going to
be returning is not a RootObject,
but a promise that when this is completed,
it will give us the type RootObject.
That's what a Task object is.
That should work, hopefully.
We'll test that out in just a moment here.
So let's go over here to our MainPage.xaml
and make a call into
that.
So let's go
var weather equals
new, well, actually, let's not do it that way.
Let's go RootObject myWeather
RootObject myWeather = OpenWeatherMapProxy.GetWeather()
RootObject myWeather = OpenWeatherMapProxy.GetWeather().
We'll give it just
a fake
latitude and longitude because I know
we're going to be hard coding that.
This has to be awaited, right?
That means this has to be async, right?
So that looks like that works, great.
Let's move that over a little bit.
Now that we have the weather, we should
be able to, for example, in the ResultTextBlock.Text,
we should be able to go
myWeather.name,
and then let's concatenate that to
myWeather.
What else can we get here?
I think if we do, if we want to get to the temperature,
we go to myWeather.main.temp
myWeather.main.temp.
There we go.
Then I think, also,
we can do this,
my... plus
myWeather dot...
What we'll get back with this weather
is it'll be a list of weather items.
We want the first weather item.
I think the other weather items are for
different hours or different days.
Then we'll say, "Give me a description
"of what the weather is."
So let's go ahead and run it.
I'm sure we'll hit some bugs
in just a moment.
Yeah.
Oh, here we go.
That's easy to fix.
I got rid of the class, so I have
to get rid of that as well.
Let's try it now.
Alright, well, we got our hot pink.
At least that's going for us.
I'll click Get Weather, and awesome.
Look, we got Dallas County.
We get the temperature is 299,
so that's Kelvin degrees.
We need to use, we can use Celsius
for those who live in the Metric System,
or Fahrenheit for those who live
in the Imperial System.
But at any rate, I was able to grab out
where I'm at currently.
So I'm in Dallas County.
This is on my local desktop.
I don't have a GPS, but it's able to triangulate
based on where my IP Address is to determine
where I'm coming from,
and it can determine that.
Then you can see here, it's light raining,
which is true.
I think it's in the mid 70s, high 70s.
We'll have to change that.
In fact, I think what I can do here,
let's go ahead and play around with this
a little bit.
We make our call out,
I think I can hit,
do this: units=imperial
units=imperial.
See if that's correct.
Yeah, so 78 degrees.
In fact, let me do one thing here with that,
with the temperature.
I'm just going to go ahead and go
convert that to an integer, and then take
the whole thing and convert it ToString,
like that.
That will get rid of the decimal.
Great.
One other thing that I want to talk about here
before we go any further, and that is
if you look at
this, you can also get to icons.
If we scroll down, there are some icons
that are associated
with.
Let me see if I search this, icon.
Yeah, you can see that it will return back
an icon as well.
So let's just,
let's have a little fun with this, actually.
Let's add an Image control.
Let's set its Name="ResultsImage"
Name="ResultsImage".
I'll just do Width="200"
Height="200".
Then what we'll do inside of here is set the
ResultImage.Source = myWeather
I think in order to get this work,
I'm going to have to act on this a little bit.
I don't think it's going to give me back,
the data that it gives us back, if we take a look
at this, like an example,
it gives us just '04n'
as the icon.
If we take a look at
this URL,
weather conditions.
Openweathermap.org/weather-conditions.
You can see that there are a bunch
of weather icons with specific names.
'01d' for daytime, '01n' for nighttime,
'02d' for daytime, so this is sunny,
partly sunny, cloudy, overcast.
It looks like they have the descriptions, too, here,
clear sky, rain, mist.
There's nine or ten of these things
with specific names.
So what my thought process is, is we can
access these
by going to
this URL, for example,
openweathermap.org/image/w/10d.png
openweathermap.org/image/w/10d.png.
Let's open that up in a new tab,
and you can see that we get that new image there.
So let's do this.
Let's grab that URL.
I copied it to my clipboard.
Let's go string icon = String.Format
string icon = String.Format
Then we'll use that for the most part,
but I know we're only going to get that little bit
right there from the
myWeather object.
So let's go myWeather dot...
There should be an icon here.
How do I get to the icon?
Oh, yeah, it's part of weather.
So weather.icon, great.
Now that we have it, we're going to set
the Source = new BitmapImage.
Yeah, and I don't have that correct,
so I'll have to add the using statement for
Windows.UI.Xaml.Media.Imaging.
So we've added that, and now I'm going to create
a new URI.
The URI will be
the string that we just formatted.
I have to tell it what kind of URI I want there.
So URIKind.Absolute.
So let's see if that works now, and let's
run the app.
Awesome.
So here's my thought.
I don't like their icons.
It makes the app look too generic.
What if supplied my own version of the icons,
and I just change wherever
we're actually accessing them?
I won't go out to
opwenweathermap.org/image/w.
I'll just go to my Assets folder here.
We'll do that, I think, in the next video.
I think that's the next thing that we'll talk about.
If not, it'll be the video after that.
We'll add that in.
At least we'll have our own icons,
and it'll look very distinctive
for the style that we're trying to achieve.
We covered a lot of ground in this video,
but we talked about a little bit of setup,
but mostly about how to get at the data.
So we've made huge strides just in this
very first video.
We'll pick it up in the next one.
Thanks.